S1: All right, so welcome, everybody.
Let's get the party started.
So just so everybody understands
what the session is about.
You know, I thought I'd just open
up a little opportunity so students
could not just read
the information about assessment,
too, but also hear a little
bit of an explanation or
a little bit of a background
on assessment, too.
And what we are expecting
from the students
and that we hope that students start
working on this assignment
as soon as possible,
if you haven't started already.
So I'm just going to show you some slides.
I know that I showed this these slides to
the students who are fully online already.
I did add a little bit more information
and hopefully everybody will
have questions at the end, because
that's the point of today.
It is asking questions, getting all your
doubts out of the way and having a clear
understanding of what you can do to
do really well in this assignment,
because I believe everybody can
do very well in this assignment.
So just explain what the assignment is.
We call it the muscle resource assignment.
It's a muscle resource
because we want it to
be something that students can go back to,
to study, refresh their memory, recall,
or even use it to teach others anatomy.
Because remember, as
a health professional,
you will be teaching
clients about anatomy.
You'll be helping them
understand their body better.
So if you have a resource that
could help them understand,
then that's even better.
And that's why we say
that this assignment,
it has to be something that's
useful for your future studies.
It can't just be something that you create
and then you're going to chuck away.
That's not useful.
You know, we don't want to waste
anybody's time here in this unit.
We would like that every
effort that you make is
for learning and it's
for useful information.
The muscle resource
assignment has two parts.
The first part is
an individual assignment.
And the second part is a group assignment.
And that's why we asked you to form groups
if you haven't formed a group yet,
because your tutorial is either
later today or tomorrow.
Don't worry, you'll still have
an opportunity to form a group.
But anyway, I'll start talking
about the parts of the assignment.
And the individual part is what
we call the written component.
So the written submission
and this is the part
of the assignment that
I've been encouraging
students to create since
pretty much since week two,
since we, too, have been saying now,
everybody, if you're going
to watch the lecture
chunks on movements of the pelvis,
just create really great notes,
really great notes on
the movements of the pelvis.
And that means you add all
the regions of the the muscle regions,
then add which muscles are
part of these muscle regions,
and then describe the characteristics
of each of these muscles.
And the main characteristics
are always action,
attachment and innovation.
And then also show some
understanding of this concept,
how you apply this information.
So, for example, how are these muscles
contracting during a certain movement,
contracting concentrically,
contracting eccentrically,
or how do they engage in
a certain exercise or
maybe do a little bit
of a movement analysis?
So those those are
the things that we do in class,
and that's what we want to see
presented in your assignment.
We want to see if you understand how
to apply anatomical information.
So that's the written component.
You know, we did ask
everybody to do a muscle
resource for everything in this unit.
But you will only submit one topic
and I'll talk about the topic later,
because there are three different topics.
But the second part of your
assignment is a group component.
So that means the groups that
you form in your tutorial,
that is the group that
you will work with so
that you can create a five minute video.
And this five minute video can be,
you know, give or take 30 seconds.
It doesn't have to be
precisely five minutes,
but definitely not over
five minutes and a half.
Not under four minutes and a half.
And in this video, what
we would like to see
are all of the group members joining,
combining their topics
and doing a movement analysis
of a certain movement,
an exercise or an occupation.
So it's really up for you to decide within
your group what you would like to analyze.
And when we talk about analyzing
a movement or analyzing an action,
we are talking about everything
that we do in the tutorials.
So in the tutorials, you know, we
normally identify where the joints
are and then we talk about
the muscles that perform movements.
And these movements happen in
the Cardinal Plains and axes of movement.
So that would be the planes in the axes.
And then it would also be
good to also describe, again,
what type of contraction is
happening in these movements.
So you see, there are quite a few things
that I did there for movement analysis.
You needed to indicate joint muscles.
Where they move, moving planes
and axes, types of contraction.
And if you're doing an exercise,
if it's an open chain
kinetic exercise or close
kinetic chain exercise.
So those are that's how you
would do the movement analysis.
It's essentially the same kind of
activity that we do in the tutorials.
But when I said combine topics,
that means that if you're
analyzing a movement,
somebody will have to
analyze the lower limb,
the other person have to analyze a trunk,
and the last person will have
to analyze the upper limb.
OK, so you're combining these
together to analyze a movement,
because every movement would
involve all parts of your body.
You know, you can't separate your body.
So even if one part is
stagnant, for example,
if you're going to analyze somebody
who is in the sitting position,
still describe what is
happening in the lower limbs.
And if that means that, you
know, the joints are just.
Just staying in one certain position in
the muscles are relaxed and that's it,
and that's the movement analysis
of that part of the body.
And so just to keep it really
clear about what we're going
to be looking at in the written
individual assignment,
we hope to see the information that
we normally cover in the labs.
OK, so that's it.
The muscles in their characteristics
and in the video component,
we hope to see the concepts
that we cover in the tutorials.
Right, so that's that's how
I would divide it very clearly
about what we expect to
see in both of them.
And again, all your assignments
relate to your classes,
and that's why coming to class
is essential right now.
What are the objectives
of this assignment?
You know, we obviously
want to make sure that
all the information that you include
is accurate and that you demonstrate
how to apply anatomical knowledge.
And then you also demonstrate
that you understand
the function of all these
structures that we covered,
because by now you would
say that, you know,
the functions are you know,
some muscles are prime movers
or they're synergize or they're
stabilizers and or they are
involved in certain exercises,
certain movements.
So that that's that's how you
would demonstrate functionality.
And that obviously it is an assignment.
So it does need to be structured.
It doesn't need to follow like
a very specific formatting,
but it does need to be structured in
a way that is clear to understand,
because just remember that
your marker will be reading
your assignment and it needs
to be easy to follow,
because if it's all over the place,
obviously that's not going to demonstrate
much knowledge or it's just
going to be incomprehensible.
So structure and formatting are things
that in general in every assignment,
it's just worth taking your
time and doing those properly.
And to help you understand
a little bit more details
like what are we looking
for in your assignment?
So let's just start with
the rubric for the muscle resource.
So that's the written component.
So in in your assessment, two fold there.
If you go into Blackbaud assessment
assessment to in this folder,
you have a lot of
information there already.
So I hope you already read all
the information in there.
And one bit of the information that you
have in there is the market rubric.
You have a marketing rubric
for the muscle resource,
the written component,
and you also have a marketing rubric
for the video and marking rubric.
They pretty much describe everything that
we expect to see in your assignment.
So we're actually telling you what
you can include in your assignment,
because those are the things that
we're going to be looking for.
And that's exactly what
I just talked about.
We can be looking for if it's accurate.
If you understand how to
apply anatomical concepts,
if you understand how to
relate that to functionality,
and that means, you know, if you
if you really demonstrate that,
you're able to describe and into.
Also creates information that
you're not just somebody who's
copying and pasting information
from other places,
like you're actually demonstrating that
you can create your own diagrams,
you can create your own
pictures, illustrations.
So that would be the functionality bit.
And lastly, the structure
and form and formatting.
And I just want to point out a few
things that are very important.
So I hope everybody's paying attention now
because this is this gets lost sometimes.
And that the format that
we would like you to
submit this assignment
is as a PDF file PDF.
And now some students ask me, why
can't I submit it any other way?
Like, why can't I submit
it is the PowerPoint
or as a word file or any other way?
I'm going to say that PDF apps
are actually the way that is
just the easiest to keep
the formatting of your assignment,
because sometimes when
we open on turn it in
or when you open it on
a different computer,
you're format can go seriously off,
because I may not have the same
program as you do or the same
version of the program that you do.
And it really messes up the formatting.
But if it's a PDF, nothing changes.
It's still the same that you submitted.
So you're pretty sure that
you know what you submitted.
So PDF is is the most.
It's the only format that we will accept
the muscle resource written component.
Make sure that you identify
yourself in this PDF.
That means you need to include your
name, your student I.D., this unit,
which is functional anatomy, and
the code is hech umb one zero zero two.
Notice that for the written component on
the topic that you're going to submit,
there is a 30 page limit.
OK, so that means that please do
not extrapolate and buy 30 pages.
I mean, a four pages, which
is the most customary size,
because honestly, you don't
need more than that.
You know, most of the better
assignments that I've seen
in these years that we've
been doing this assignment,
I most of the better assignments are about
15 pages long or even less sometimes,
but they definitely don't need to be 30.
I feel that once it gets
to 30 and above becomes
very messy and becomes very loose,
information like the information doesn't
really connect with each other,
and it's just not that useful again,
because if you have the muscle
research that's over 50 pages long,
then, well, it's hard to find
the information, isn't it?
So it has to be something
that's quick and easy to see.
So 30 page limit.
There is no lower limit.
If you manage to I don't know
if you want to create, for example,
a huge info graphic or if you want
to create just a big poster, then.
Yeah, that's what you're going to submit.
And it's just one one page.
Right.
Just make sure that we're able to zoom in
and read it to just remember structure
formatting does mean readability as
well, as I put up here, readability,
because some students, sometimes they have
taken pictures of their assignments
and the picture quality is so poor that
we actually cannot read what's on it.
And if we can't read what's on it,
we can't really measure
any of these things,
we can't measure for accuracy
or application or or functionality.
And then students miss
out on all the marks
because they took really bad pictures.
So be aware that as
long as we can read it,
as long as it's organized
in a logical manner.
Properly identified, not over
30 pages, but no lower limit.
And also, obviously, it
has to be evidence based.
Because we don't think
that it's appropriate
to use incorrect information.
OK, I see a picture that I was
asked that's a good question.
So the the 30 page limit is per person.
It's per individual.
Because remember that this
part of the assignment
is an individual assignment.
You're going to submit it individually
through your own Turnitin portal.
You're not going to have to
submit it for the rest of
your group and you're not
going to have to combine.
This component of the muscle resource,
you're just going to submit
it yourself under 30 pages.
Yes, the 30 pages includes the references,
as I said, you really don't need 30 pages.
OK, so I try to keep it more concise,
try to keep it in a way that you
can clearly see everything.
Yeah.
So try to try to do it that way.
But each individual have a 30 page limit.
And that's it.
It must contain a reference list.
And citations, everybody citations,
INTECH citations, you know,
when you write down the information next
to the to the you have a paragraph
and you have to write down where
you got that information from.
So it's usually the author's
last names and a year date.
You do need to have that for
some of the information,
but not all the information.
So I'm going to say which ones you needed
for and which ones don't need it for.
Again, this is important.
So pay attention.
You do need to have InTech citations
for things than if you looked up.
Also, if you looked up
somewhere, you know,
in a textbook or if you looked up
in a scientific journal article,
if you looked at the website,
just reference them,
you know, you use it that information.
However, there are some information
that are the same everywhere.
So, for example, muscle's
the characteristics of the muscles.
So muscle attachments,
actions and innovation.
Those are the same in most
of the resources out there.
So I don't need you to reference them
because they're going to be the same.
And don't worry about keeping them
in the same structure either,
because it's going to there's going
to be a lot of the same thing.
So that can't be considered plagiarism.
If you write down the correct
attachments, action and innovation,
those things are probably going
to be the same everywhere.
But they're essential information to have
so that you do not need to reference.
You do not need to.
But everything else you do
need to cite in reference.
You need to cite everything
else that you include.
So, for example, if you
looked up an exercise
or if you looked up an occupation,
if you looked up a movement,
if you looked up an injury
example, then you do need to
cite and reference where you
got that information from.
And obviously, it's important to look
up credible resources, credible ones.
That means the textbooks
that we recommend.
So clinically oriented anatomy.
I hope everybody has that
reference in their assignment,
because that's the main reference
that we use in this unit.
So everybody should have
clinically oriented
anatomy and their reference
list, everybody.
And then there the other
ones that are really good,
like Color Atlas Anatomy, that
uses just cadaveric images.
There's also the online resources
that we provide, like anada media.
I anatomy anatomy viewer, all those are
provided there on your blackboard.
So use them.
And if you find anything else, you know,
there are some websites that
are pretty good for exercises.
I look up physical pedia all the time.
Physio, your PDA is good radio
area is very good for anatomy.
It has some radiological
structures there as well.
So if you want to compare
x rays and more eyes,
those are pretty that's
a pretty good website.
Not that it's necessary,
but it's it's a good website
to learn anatomy and applied
in the different way.
And injuries.
Ortho bullets.
Ortho Bullets is a great website as well.
Also, bullet has a lot of
musculoskeletal injuries,
examples and treatments, diagnoses.
So a lot of extra
information that we don't
necessarily cover in function anatomy.
But if it interests you, you know,
you can get a lot of
information there as well.
And I'm not really like I feel
that I can hug in Khan Academy,
they are secondary sources, very
much like most of my material.
The material that we upload and function
anatomy is very much a secondary source.
And as you may be aware, secondary sources
shouldn't really be referenced.
You shouldn't really reference them.
But obviously, we are all working
on evidence based information.
OK.
So just make sure that if you
are using our lecture slides,
Khan Academy or Ken Hubb,
then at least have a look and see
where they got that information
from and then reference
the primary source.
OK.
It's very important, again, to
reference a primary source,
and that's just for
general academic writing.
Primary sources are the ones
that you have to reference
unless you can't find the primary source.
Then you cite in reference
the secondary source.
So just be aware that it's not acceptable.
To reference the lecture
slides, it's not acceptable.
Because, as I said, the primary
source that we mainly use.
Are more clinically oriented anatomy.
And that's the one that
needs to be referenced.
OK.
Hopefully, that was clear.
I think that some questions came through.
So I'm sorry if I'm not keeping up.
And I have one, if we use slide
format, can we put in tech citations
and just like footer instead of
putting right beside the text?
That's a good question camera,
and I'm going to say.
It depends what you're citing.
If you're if you copy
like if you're citing
information and written information,
then that's OK to put it on the footer or,
you know, preferably nearby
the information where where you're at,
because that's the whole
point of sighting.
It's just to show where that
information comes from.
So as long as it's nearby that
information, and that's fine.
If it's really far away,
then that's not really OK,
because then I won't know where
you got that information
from and images you need to
site it under the images.
Like if you're if you
copy and paste an image,
then you need to put
the references right below the image.
It's pretty much the whole entire
reference below each image
that you copy and paste
if you don't reference images.
That's plagiarism.
OK, that said, that's
a copyright infringement.
All those images are copy written.
Even the ones you find on the Internet.
So, again, if you copy and paste
and you do not alter that image at all,
then you need to site it under each image
and then reference it
in the reference list.
OK.
All right, good stuff.
Let's just see here for the next
rubric is just a little bit different,
as you can see, this is for the video.
And in the video, we're
going to be looking
at a slightly different things.
For example, we're going
to be seeing, obviously,
the content, the concepts that we learned.
So, for example, description of
exercises or occupations, you know,
the joints and muscles that
are involved in a movement.
What type of contraction
they're performing.
If you include surface anatomy to
indicate where those structures
are and that you're able to do
the movement analysis effectively,
you know, that's really good
because it really synthesizes
all the information that we've
been learning in this unit.
So that's where we would
like to see in the video.
But obviously, you've
got to make sure that
all this information is integrated.
You are looking at all the main topics
lower limb, a prelim and trunk,
and that your communication
is clear and engaging.
And obviously, it is a video.
So digital competence
is going to be looked
at if you're able to film something.
There may be some editing
involved, though.
I understand we are not
Hollywood producers and we
shouldn't spend too much
time perfecting this.
So just create a video that contains all
this information and that's organized.
And that's what we're
going to be looking at.
Doesn't need to have all the flares in all
the days and hours of work behind it.
OK, and obviously you're going
to be in both assignments
and both not both assigned
to both components,
you're going to be measured
on a scale from one to five.
Obviously, it's a zero.
If you don't submit anything
by if you submit something,
then it's going to be on a one to five.
And I only put down
the description here of the fives,
because that's what I would
like everybody to aim for.
You know, you want to
demonstrate in depth,
accurate information that's
clearly and logically
structure that's clear and engaging,
and that it has pretty
good audio visual quality
and it's in within the time limit.
OK, so if you can manage
to hit all these targets,
then that's it, then it should be fine.
Note that the written
component is worth 20 marks
and the video component is worth 20 marks.
So in total, this assignment is worth
40 percent of your marks, 40 percent.
So this is the most heavily
weighted assignment that you have.
So when that you have
the most time to work on.
And it's the one that as well as
long as you follow, if you you know,
if you're coming to classes,
if you're keeping up with the content,
and if you are checking
the rubrics of what you include,
then you should do really
well and it really well.
And I just want to give
you all a few examples
of what we had submitted previously.
I do add at the end of each module,
examples of previous assignments,
examples of really good
previous assignments.
Obviously, cherry picked
the ones that are the best for you.
And I just want to show you the format.
So let's just start here on
this left hand side where
you can see some flash
cards and flash cards or,
you know, great ways to learn.
If you create your own flash cards
and you add all the necessary information,
speak to the functions and actions.
And as you can see here on these
flash cards, the student,
she took a very generic phone
image just off the Internet.
But then she drew over it.
So she actually created something.
She modified this image.
So since she modified this
image, so what she did,
she doesn't need to reference it
because it's her own creation.
So there was no need to
reference all of this.
But unless at the very end, at
the very end, create a reference list.
And obviously, I think
that the information was
taken from more clinically
oriented anatomy.
Another good example are
fold-out fold-out cier.
For example, the student drew
a skeleton in a big cardboard
cardboard bow on those
hard pieces of paper.
And then she drew
the muscles on colored papers,
cut them out in their shape
and layered them over the skeleton.
So this shows a really good understanding
of attachments, shapes, layering.
This is really good.
And behind each of these muscles,
you would fold out and there
would be the information
behind each of these muscles,
the attachments,
the actions, the nerve supply.
And at the end, she also
included some exercise examples.
Another good example was a workout guide,
the student had a gym in his backyard,
so he pictured himself doing exercises.
He highlighted the muscles that were being
targeted in each one of these exercises.
And then he created tables to add more
information to show his understanding.
What is an open chain kinetic exercise?
Common mistakes?
What are the agonists or
the prime movers of the exercise?
So you can see here that he went
beyond what was being asked of him.
Not only did he talk about
the main characteristics,
but he also analyzed them
in in a very useful way,
in a very functional way.
And the next example that
I'm going to give you is
probably the one that
students prefer the most.
And that's creating a notebook.
OK, so a notebook is a really
good way to learn, obviously,
and it's absolutely
encouraged and accepted.
This one here is a notebook,
but it was created as
an electronic notebook.
And he drew this.
He drew this interior thigh
region in the muscles,
added all the information next to it,
even added the picture of
a muscle of a muscle here.
That's very we don't mention it
much to the articulators journal.
At the end, he included
exercises to show how these
muscles would be engaged
in these exercises.
Note that he didn't.
Do an exercise for each individual muscle.
You know, because that's not how
muscles work, muscles work as groups.
So you don't have to give an example
for each individual muscle.
But usually as a group.
So one example for a group.
Yeah, that's highly recommended
because it's showing
us that you understand how
to apply this knowledge.
So showing us an exercises, showing it.
I had a student last year
who was a yoga instructor
and she analyzed yoga
postures, looked excellent.
Excellent.
I should upload her assignment as well.
And she also analyzed
lengthening exercises,
not just strengthening, but lengthening.
So that was really good.
And again, that's why I'm
giving you a few options.
It's not supposed to be one
just in one very specific way.
It can be the way that
you think that you're
going to enjoy creating the most.
And it's going to be more
useful for you in the future.
OK.
Obviously, pump cars are
quicker and easier.
The fold-out.
It's for somebody who likes to
do the arts and crafts side.
This student really likes
exercising in this student here.
I think just.
Good package here as well, right?
Good, good.
Good points in the artsy side and and,
you know, in just kind of integrated,
I think that the integrated
the information here very well.
That was the main thing that
we were very impressed with.
It was with the integration.
Now, I want to just separate
one thing from another,
and that is when we say that
you should be creative.
We don't mean artsy.
We don't mean that you
need to be a Picasso, OK?
You don't have to be artsy.
Create art.
Being creative means that
you are creating something,
that you are generating the images,
you are drawing them, you
are taking pictures,
you're drawing it on your skin.
I have some students who have done
like surface anatomy assignments,
and they drew on their
skin or they took pictures
of themselves and then drew on the images.
And, you know, so there they
created this information.
They didn't copy
and paste it from elsewhere.
Copy and pasting obviously
is not going to get as many
marks because it's just not
something that you create.
And if you don't create
the process, you'll learn less.
So that's just how it's measured.
If you create something, you're
going to be marked higher.
Do you copy and paste?
It's going to be lower.
OK.
Just keep that in mind.
All right.
And I should change this, actually.
I'm sorry, this is incorrect here.
The the due dates are correct.
They're both due in week
thirteen at the last day.
So Friday week 13 for the video
you're going to uploaded
on to YouTube and you're
going to create a link.
OK, you're going to create a link
and then you're going to submit it.
So you're not going to
send it to this email.
You're actually going to
submit it on Blackbaud.
There's going to be
a blackboard submission point.
OK, so we created this recently.
We recently found out how to do it.
That's why I forgot to change this.
But there's going to be
a blackboard submission points,
and that's where you're going
to submit the link to.
I do want to highlight that, you know,
you give yourself some time to create
the video and upload it on YouTube
depending on the size of the video.
It can take hours to
upload a link to YouTube.
So that means you definitely
shouldn't be doing this.
30 minutes before the assignment is due,
because it's going to be late
if if you try to do that.
If you notice on your program calendar,
you actually have you actually will finish
pretty much all your topics in week 10.
Week 10 is the last time
that we have new content.
So that means everybody can finish
their written assignment by week 10.
Everybody, including those who have
shrunk as their as their topic.
So if you completed a week 10,
then you have weeks 11
and 12 to work on the video.
And hopefully you do meet with with
your group in weeks 11 and 12,
because that's when you
should be creating the video.
It's going to take time.
OK, so give yourselves that time.
And once you do create the video,
you're going to uploaded to YouTube again,
takes a few hours of
a few minutes or a few
hours to upload it and create the link.
You can create a private link
so that not everybody has access to it.
OK, so if you don't want it to be
out there for everybody to see.
Create a private link and then upload it
through the Blackwatch submission point.
Same here with the written assignment.
You're going to it's going to be
due on the same time and again,
don't leave it at
the last minute to submit it,
because there's always
something that happens
with Turnitin that you just don't expect.
So, for example, you shoot something like
an assignment that cannot
be scanned for words.
It's not going to be
accepted for through turned
it in because turn it in scanned words.
So usually if you're going to
take pictures of your assignment,
then that means that you at
least have to have a cover
page with words on them
in at least 20 words.
So that means that you need
to create a word file,
combine it with the pictures,
and then submit it like that.
So it's recognized by Turnitin.
And if you try to keep submitting it,
it's going to get you error is
not going to let you submitted.
Another thing that it
doesn't let you submit,
if it's the file is too big,
if it's over a hundred,
I think it's over a hundred.
Let me just double check here.
I didn't put it up.
It's in your.
Yeah, it's definitely in
your assessment too folder.
I think it's over 100 megabytes.
Turn it in.
Doesn't accept it.
So you got to make sure that your
assignment is also under a hundred
megabytes so that you can
submit it on to turn it in.
So there are few things that you
need to troubleshoot sometimes,
and you don't want to do that half
an hour before the assignment is due.
Or else it's going to be like.
And as I said, the muscle assignment.
You can finish it by week 12.
Everybody can finish it so everybody
can finish it by week 10.
So we're going to open
the submission point in week 10,
and we hope that students
start submitting it by then.
OK.
You shouldn't be waiting
until the last week,
the very last day to
submit your assignment,
because remember that you have other
assignments to do on the same week.
And if you think that you're going to
submit everything at the same time,
it's just not going to happen.
So give yourself enough time to
submit both of these components.
Because if you don't, then late penalties
do apply if it's a few minutes
after use of the do time
and date, then it's five percent.
Then if it's over 24 hours,
then it's 15 percent.
And then from then onwards,
it's like 10 percent.
And after five days and you
just don't get anything.
So just make sure they use them.
Submit an all time.
And I guess we're the last
things is you have to be mindful
of plagiarism by not copy
and paste indirect information,
by having a reference list
and referencing the images that you use.
And, you know, just make sure
that you submit a PDF file,
turn it in, and it's something
that can scan words.
OK, because it needs to
be able to scan words.
It can't just be images.
So at least create a Covid
page with your name.
The title of the assignment,
the name of the unit,
your student I.D., you
know all that information.
Your topic.
So your topic is going
to be one of these ones.
Each member of the group will
choose one of these topics trunk,
upper limb or lower limb.
And these groups of three
or four people, you know,
if there's three people, each
one will choose each topic.
And if there's four people,
then two people in the group will
be able to do the same topic.
But individual assignments, it's not that
they can work on the same assignment.
They're still going to be doing individual
assignments on the same topic.
That's it.
Everybody must do a different topic,
because remember that the video is
about combining all these topics.
If there is a member in your
group that does not collaborate,
that doesn't answer emails,
and that just doesn't show
up to film the video.
Please let me know.
Please email me saying
the day we filmed it,
this person did not show up because they
can't get grades if they don't show up.
And if they don't do their part
because they have to do their part,
that means if they have the trunk,
they have to show they
have to contribute to that
video component and analyzing the truck.
So everybody has to engage in this video.
You can't just leave it to
your peers to create a video.
That's why everybody needs
to have a different topic.
And if the student doesn't
show up, it's not going to.
It's not going to harm
the others in your group,
because essentially I'm going to be
looking at you all as individuals.
OK, because everybody has an individual
part in both of these components.
So don't be worried if somebody
doesn't show up in your group,
you know, try to contact them, obviously.
But if they just don't
collaborate, don't worry,
you're not going to be disadvantaged.
But you do need to tell
me what's happening.
Let me just say a few questions
that I got just recently,
so when it says most of the lower limbs.
Is it all muscles like quads,
hamstrings, foot gastrocnemius?
So, Sean.
Yeah, pretty much it.
So everything that's in each module,
pretty much if you think
about them as modules,
everything that is in
module one is a lower limb.
Everything that's module
two is upper limb.
Everything that's module three is trunk.
So if you think about lower limb,
you started in the pelvic region.
That's iliac muscles, gluteal
muscles, medial thigh muscles.
Anterior thigh, posterior
thigh, posterior leg,
anterior leg, lateral
leg and intrinsic foot.
So all of those would be included in
the lower limb muscle assignment.
And let's see, I have another.
If there's a cap.
Upload the muscle resource.
Yeah, so that's it.
So if you have a cap, you will have
the same turn it in submission points.
So you you know, everybody has their
own identifier and turn it in.
And those who have caps,
we have them already
indicated on Blackboard
that you will not be
penalized if you submitted
a few days after the due date,
but only the written component.
OK, so the written component is the one
that you do have an extension for.
But everybody needs to submit the video at
the same time because
it's a group assignment.
And I have quite a few questions.
Let me just go through it.
Maximum pages is counted
per person or as a group.
OK, so 30 pages per person.
So per topic.
So you add your own individual topic,
you have 30 pages maximum, no lower limit.
So I can definitely be shorter than that.
To do we have to include all
the muscles of the upper limbs
or can we select the ones
we like to make notes for?
Well, all the ones that are in
the module to start its module, too.
So it is pretty much all
the ones that we covered.
OK.
You just have to at least mention them.
You can't focus on the prime movers.
Absolutely.
But you do need to mention them,
especially if we if I've
presented their attachments.
So, for example, if you noticed in
the lower limbs we went through,
the attachments have pretty
much all the muscles
except for the intrinsic foot muscles,
because we don't really need to understand
how they function individually.
And it's very similar with the upper limb.
Yes, it is important to
know the attachments
of most of the upper limb muscles.
But we do not go into too many details
on the intrinsic hand muscles.
So like we have intrinsic foot muscles,
we have intrinsic hand muscles.
So, again, we don't really
need the attachments
for the intrinsic muscles.
So I would say it that way,
and with the trunk, it's very similar.
There are many muscles that are part
of the intrinsic back muscle region.
But the deepest layer, we don't really.
We don't really focus too much
on the attachments because
there's such small muscles
around joints that they
stare stabilizers and we don't
really need to understand
their attachments to
understand their function.
And then number three, a few weeks ago,
I received an email on a deferred exam.
I wonder if.
I wonder if it is for those
who have requested the friend
exam or if it's for everyone
who is taking the course.
OK.
No, it's just for those
who deferred the exam.
So you know that we had the mid
semester lab exam Monday and Tuesday
and students who were sick or who
had to defer for any reason.
Those were the ones who
had to defer the exam.
And so they went through
the online application
process and it was just informing
them when the deferred dates are
the deferred dates are in December.
I've already confirmed
the dates on the 6th of September.
Of December.
Yeah, because that's when we
can run the lab exams again,
as you may understand.
We can set up Alembic in tuition
free week or during classes.
We just don't have
the time or space for that.
So all the deferred exams
happen in December.
But if you completed your
exam on Monday or Tuesday,
you're done with it.
That's it.
You don't have to do anything else.
All right, good questions.
And I guess just to finish here with this
muscle resource in your tutorials,
what you were asked to do was
to form groups of three.
Everybody needed to choose
a topic so that the three or four
people in your group had to
choose a different topic.
And then you had to email
HMV one zero zero two
with the following subject
assessment to group.
And it had to have your group members
and the topics that
each one of them chose.
And a quick video idea.
Just say we chose Adonal.
We chose plucking the eyebrows.
You know, that was the video
idea, which is completely fine.
So if you had your tutorials, this
is what you should have done by now.
OK.
All the groups will be formed
by tomorrow afternoon.
So please send it to this email
so that we can create it and.
If you did not go to your tutorial,
first of all, bad, you should have gone.
It was required for all students to go.
The students who emailed me with
justifications, I said, great.
We have a solution for you.
We have a group for you.
That's fine.
But those of you who did
not go did not justify
why we didn't come to the tutorial.
We're just going to put you in
random groups of three people,
three or four people, and it'll
be up to you to organize that,
organize when to meet
what topics each one of
you will have to submit
and what video idea.
So there's not going to be
an opportunity to do this in class again,
because this was this was
the opportunity to do it.
So I don't really want to hear complaints.
If you don't like your
group or if you feel
like you don't want to do that topic,
you're just going to
have to sort itself out.
If you didn't have your tutorial
yet, go go to the tutorial,
because then you will have
an idea which topic to do.
And you will have had
the opportunity to discuss an idea,
see your peers or see your group
members and maybe discuss when
it will be a good time to film
the video in week 11 or week 12.
So what are the groups chosen
randomly, can we decide?
Yes, Sean, that's it.
So for those of you who have
not had your tutorial yet,
you will be able to choose your groups.
So within your tutorial group,
if you already work with two
or three people on a normal basis,
then you can talk to them
and then form the group.
OK, so if you haven't had your
tutorial yet, go form your groups.
Email HMV one zero zero
two with the topics
that each one of you
chose in a video idea,
because and then you can also
discuss with your tutors.
What?
Any questions that you may have or ask
them for any feedback resistance?
So, yeah, go to your tutorials.
And that's why I said everybody is
is like everybody is obligated to
go to your tutorial this week because
it's part of your assignment.
It's part of your assessment.
It's worth 40 percent of your marks.
So those who did not show up to their
tutorials this week, I'm just.
I don't even know how.
I'm speechless, really, that they didn't
go to class and then justify it.
OK.
All right, but obviously you
are all doing very well.
He showed up to this collaborates
session, asked great questions.
That's really all I had to do.
So I'm just going to stay here for another
few minutes answering questions.
So I got a question here from Cameron
saying for movement analysis,
how many movements do we
need to break down to?
We analyze the movements of one big
occupation or do we focus on two
or three smaller tasks that are
part of the bigger occupation?
Excellent question.
Camera.
You know, don't don't try
to do too much, obviously.
So if you're thinking about
an example of somebody
stacking a can in a supermarket shelf.
So what I would be analyzing
is that reaching movement
and maybe the return
movement if there is time.
KING because you're going to have to
analyze everything in that reaching
movement and that could be starting
all the way from the foot.
So, for example, your.
Talo Kraj Lindt will need
to go into planter flexion
using the gastrocnemius and slowly as or
tricep souri muscles
contracting concentrically
in these movements happen in the frontal.
So in these moves happen in the sagittal
plane around the coronal axis.
So this see that you're going
to do it on the ankle and then
you're going to analyze
what's happening on the need.
The knee is an extension.
So is the hip.
The trunk is stabilizing.
The vertebral column and the shoulder
joint is going into flexion.
Your elbow is extending your muscles.
So your interior form muscles
are grabbing that can
and then you're flexing
to put it on the shelf.
So do you see how I went
through pretty much from
the lower limb to
the all the way to placing
the shelf down and analyzing
this movement according to,
you know, the joints, muscles?
The obvious, I didn't do it completely.
I skipped a few steps here.
The one I did the most was the ankle one.
But you would be analyzing all the way up.
So obviously, you're going to be
focusing on the main movements.
The main movements here would be plenty of
flexion infliction of the shoulder girdle
region or flexion of
the Gleno Humera joint
in this capital, thoracic joints.
OK, so those are the ones that
are going to be analyzing.
And if there's time to do
the return movement, then great.
But definitely not explaining
how to entirely play football.
You know, that's just
going to be way too much
and definitely doesn't
fit in five minutes.
So choose one movement.
Of one occupation or sports or physical
activity or movement and focus on that.
Got it.
Excellent.
And it could be big task,
could be a little task.
I use the idea of plucking your eyebrows.
That's still OK.
You know, what you're going
to do here is going to
analyze is the person
in sitting or standing,
where are the joints in space,
which movements are happening?
And if there's a movement happening,
are these movements happening?
Which Cardinal Plains of movement
around which plant, in which plane,
around which axis, in which
muscles are engaged in,
how are they contracting?
So if you're pulling together
all this information,
then, hey, that's a good video.
That's a good explanation.
Does anybody else have
any further questions?
I must say that I'm very impressed with
the quality of the questions here.
I think then.
We covered pretty much everything.
The questions help me remember
some important details,
important aspects of the assignment.
I really hope this session
helped you understand
your assignment a bit better.
And we have one more question.
So we've chosen a mother
with lower back pain
to hold a baby for
prolonged period of time.
Can we choose standing only
with no movement as well?
You can.
But I would say there is there
is still things happening.
And by things, I mean, your joints
are still in a certain position.
So describe those positions, describe
how the joints are positioned.
So in which Kardinal
plane around which axis,
and think about how
the muscles are working
when the mother is holding the baby.
Because there's a lot of
isometric contraction
happening here in this in this activity.
And then you can also
think around, you know,
a mother probably doesn't
just stand holding the baby.
The mother probably stands
bouncing the baby up and down.
So think about right.
So how is this bouncy movement
like what's actually happening?
Which muscles are contributing
to this movement or to this?
It ends up being an occupation that led
to this occupation of holding the baby.
So I guess, yes, you absolutely can.
As I said, not all of
the joints need to be moving
at the same time to do
the movement analysis.
Just describe what's
happening in these joints
and how these muscles are working.
OK, good stuff.
Let's see volleyball spike to contribute
to all the muscles for the video.
Absolutely, yeah, volleyball
spike is excellent.
So I guess then it
depends on where you're.
Starting from I would assume that you
would be starting from, you know,
jumping up, so you would start
actually from the very.
From the ankle joint region
and moving up to what's
happening in the new what's
happening in the hip,
what's happening in the vertebral column,
and ultimately, you know,
the arm that has gone up into
flexion and is going to
extension during a spike.
So, yeah, that's a that's a very
awesome movement channelize.
I like the creativity,
everyone, this is a very good.
All right, sounds really good, everyone.
I'll probably just stay for another five
minutes in case you have any questions.
If you don't have any other questions,
then I think this is pretty much it.
I'd like to thank you all for
hanging in there and asking
such great questions and good
luck on your assignment.
You know, like I don't
mind having a look at the.
Neither do your tutors, like
bringing your assignment
into class so they could
have a quick look.
And quick feedback, like quick
feedback is considerable.
We can't spend 30 minutes on each
assignment giving you feedback.
But if I could just have a quick
look and say, oh, this looks good,
or, hey, how about you add
more information on this?
You know, this could give
you some good pointers.
So if you start your assignment short,
your tutor and the tutor could give
you a few pointers along the way.
Then it's less of a surprise at the end
when you submit it and get your grades.
All right, thank you.
Brian, I'm going to well.
This link will stay on collaborate.
So if you click on collaborate, you know,
this recording will stay there.
As long as it's a recent recording,
it'll stay there, if it's not there,
that means you just have to go
back to a different time window,
but it'll stay there for a few weeks.
I'm also going to copy
the link and send it out as
an announcement so that
the students who couldn't
make it today could watch
it and be very clear
where to click on to watch the video.
Yes, in the video assignment,
so I'm going to sneeze.
So sorry about that.
Yes, the video component is five minutes.
And you can go over 30 seconds under
30 seconds, that's completely fine.
Just not too much over those times.
Yeah, because if it starts to get
closer to 6:00 or close to four,
then that's really not the time limit.
You're going to get some marks taken out
if you do long videos
or short or too short.
See what muscles trunk
and back, move the scapula,
or would that be the upper limb?
Yeah, so good question, Sean.
I know that they look like
that's Kapoor's on the back,
but it's more involved
with the upper limbs.
So all those xou up into killer muscles,
they are part of the upper limb.
If your topic is the trunk,
then that means then
you're going to be looking at the back,
the intrinsic back muscles as well.
And that starts with.
Your neck muscles,
so that would be, you know,
your spleen is Kaputa spleen services,
followed by the erectors spiny muscles.
Then you have the deep
and minor deep layers.
And let's not forget that you
would also have the respiratory
muscles and the abdominal
muscles for trunk.
So it's everything that's in
the axial skeleton region.
But the muscles that move
the scapula, that upper limb.
And no problem.
Good questions.