- Good afternoon, everyone.
I'm Paul Gallagher.
I'm LNG agricultural land use
planning officer with DPI agriculture.
Thank you for joining us today on this webinar to discuss
the preliminary draft state significant agricultural land.
I'd like to begin by acknowledging the traditional
custodians of the various lands on which we meet.
today.
I'm presenting from the age-old country, and I wish to
pay my respects to the elders past, present and emerging.
And I also like to extend those respects to any
First Nations people attending this webinar today.
We have close to 100 people on online today.
So if you could please keep your microphones
on mute during the presentations, if you have
any questions, please post them in the chat
function, which is at the bottom of the page.
And we'll work through those questions
in the question session at the end.
We may be able to invite you to come off mute and
discuss the questions but please be mindful that with
so many people on the on the call, we need to keep
the discussion the 16th so everybody can have a say.
If we don't give them any questions today, when the time we
have, then we'll provide answers to them and put them in our
Frequently Asked Questions section on our exhibition page.
We'll also make the presentation slides available on
the exhibition page after the second webinar tomorrow.
And it would be great if you can make
your name and organization appear.
But your video and you can do this by hovering
over the video, clicking on the little three
dots and renaming yourself and your organization.
Today's webinar will provide you with a background
information on the preparation of the preliminary
draft state significant agricultural land map.
The intention is to give you a better understanding of
the process used to create the map and its potential use
to inform any submission you want to make on the map.
DPI agriculture's manager of agricultural land use planning
tomorrow apprentice will speak about the background of the
preparation of the map, how it came about, and how it might
be used in future and then DPI agriculture's agricultural
land use planning officer Helen squires will speak about
what the map shows the criteria used to develop it.
The feedback we are seeking and how to make an
submission or not now invite tomorrow apprentice
manager agricultural land use planning and DPI to speak.
- Hi, everyone, my name is Tamara apprentice, and I'm
the manager of the agricultural land use planning team.
As Paul just mentioned, Thank you, Paul.
And I'm very proud to be here.
Talking to you all about a map.
As most of you will know, a map has been something
that we have contemplated for agricultural land in
the planning framework for quite a number of years.
I just like to start by talking about
the planning framework more generally.
So we can see across the planning framework
that there's differing levels of maturity,
respect, responding to the relative pressures
that each of the sector has faced over time.
- For example, in residential and commercial areas, extensive
planning has been undertaken to identify locations for
high density development, in comparison to in the rural
areas where they've been subject to less relative pressure.
And we've seen that there's often incompatible
uses clustered within rural zones which have been
applied inconsistently, often across the state.
In response to this, what we're seeing is
an increasing level of land use conflict.
And that's causing financial and emotional
hardship on some of the residents and also
increasing compliance burdens for council.
agriculture plays an important role in the
stability and the growth of regional economies.
It also supplies food and fiber to our cities.
And particularly down around the Sydney region we're
looking at we've seen recently, a call out for fresh
food deserts and the light because of the pressures
pushing agriculture further from those city centers.
agricultural land also plays important roles and
depending on location in the state, they can provide
green backdrops, heat sinks and tourism locations.
But what has been found during a recent process by the New
South Wales Agriculture Commissioner was that more assertive
and explicit planning was needed for agriculture to achieve
regional growth and agricultural production targets.
During this process, the consultation revealed that there
was almost universal agreement on the need for a map.
agriculture continues to compete across the rural
landscape and is finding itself under pressure from
urban encroachment and land fragmentation as well.
It's hoped that the map might assist to better
inform decisions about the allocation of rural land.
It's also hoped that the map might help educate the
communities and decision makers about the relative
importance of various sectors of agricultural land.
We know that agricultural land is not all equal,
across 1516, before the drought really took
hold, we know that 17% of our land produced
about 56% of agricultural value in the state.
So it's between six and seven times more productive,
that's 17% of the state is the other 83%, you know,
produce point 5% of that on a percentage basis.
We've developed this map in the hope that we can
enable a discussion, in the first instance about what
should be mapped, and what that map might look like.
We know that the map has come out in a very
preliminary draft iteration, we understand that there's
issues in some of the data sets underpinning it.
And we're really hoping to get some feedback
from yourselves through this process to
try and help us better prepare this map.
The next question that we're getting
frequently is how will the map be used?
And there's really no easy answer
to this question at this stage.
So the Agriculture Commissioner made some recommendations
about how policy could be implemented, which would
help implementation of the map at this stage, the
government has not had a chance to consider its response.
And the whole of government response will
have to be prepared across agencies as
well, to say how the map should be used.
Those negotiations will continue over the next few months.
And so at this point in time, the map as it's exhibited,
is not proposed to be used in any particular manner.
What we do know or what we are proposing, at
least is that the maps not going to be used as
a replacement for base cell in the mining zip,
that map was produced for a particular purpose.
This map has been produced for a different purpose.
So it's not proposed to replace that map at this stage.
It's also not proposed to replace important
farmland mapping on the north coast.
So the agriculture Commissioner's report, some of
you might have read highlighted, that was probably
one of the better ways that we could implement this
map over time once we had more confidence in it.
But until that, until that happens, we're not
proposing that those maps be replaced at this point.
The map may also need to be supplemented by work to
identify locally or regionally significant farmland.
So we know that certain regions have particular
attributes that need to be called out.
And this map certainly shouldn't prevent that occurring.
It's just to try and help provide consistency
across the state as to where our most
productive land in the state should be.
And I think that's about it from me.
Paul, were there any immediate questions?
Or shall I hand over to yourself or Helen?
- No, thanks, Tamara.
We don't have any questions in the chat at this stage.
So hello, if you'd like to speak
on the construction of the map.
Thank you pool swipe tool.
So how is the map prepared the site significant
ag land map, as Tamara mentioned earlier,
is definitely in its early draft stage.
And it's predominantly brought together
by three groups of information.
The first area is we're talking about
land with certain biophysical attributes.
So such things such as water availability,
soil and land capability, soil type, and slope.
And we'll touch more on some of
those details in the next slide.
But basically, we're looking at characteristics
that are known and that don't readily change.
The next group of information that we're
looking at the irrigated areas across the state.
So when we describe irrigated areas that might be
land that has only one or two irrigations throughout
the year, or irrigation areas that heavily rely
on throughout the whole growing season irrigated
lands produce a significantly large volume of
produce per hectare compared to non irrigated lands.
So this is why we've sort of pulled it out
and identify that on its own merit there.
Because a significant amount of infrastructure and
investment from both government and obviously from a private
industry has gone into to this particular method of farming.
We know that water licenses are traded, and
so that the location of water licenses haven't
actually been used to help identify the
irrigation areas in this particular draft of them.
That may be something that we
will look at labor down the track.
We've identified irrigation areas through the use of the
Australian collaborative land use management program data.
So that's a national data Bit that looks at
land use management across different times.
So obviously, taking into consideration, droughts
and other climatic instances that affect irrigation
use, we've taken a 10 year snapshot of that.
So from 2007 through to the 2017 data sets.
The other group of information, as Tamara
mentioned before, is the state and regionally
significant farmland on the north coast.
So the Agriculture Commissioner report pulled
this out and identified it that is quite a
rigorous and scientifically backed data set.
So the Northern Rivers farmland project identified
the North Coast mapping in this area in 2005.
And then the mid north coast mapping came through in 2008.
So it is primarily based on
biophysical characteristics as well.
But it was had a lot more input from the farming communities
and reference groups, and then it was tested and verified
by soil scientists and industry leaders in that space.
So they're the three sort of groups of information
that we're using to help build the map at this stage.
And just, as Tamara mentioned, the North Coast
farmland mapping has been used in the planning
system or planning framework since 2005.
And has been accepted by planning
authorities and the community for some time.
Just I'm just having a trying to get away from it.
Next slide there.
Before I dive into what we use to build the map, I just
want to touch base on things that we didn't use, or
we've excluded from the development of the SSA l map.
So naturally, we excluded all national parks
areas, state forests, wetlands, and land
that has a slope higher than 18 degrees.
And that was based off the steep
and Holly erodible lands dataset.
From the NB RM map.
We also want to identify that remote that
the areas mapped adjust in the LEP zones
that are permissible for agriculture.
So we're looking at the rural use zone, so the
primary production zone, rural landscape, farming
production, small lots and the transition zone.
We also have many councils that are currently
conducting land use strategies at present.
And so we know that a lot of agriculture is
currently undertaken in the environmental
management, environmental living zones.
And we're just wanting to identify what
was happening in those spaces as well.
The Food Matters are also used in the
north coast, because of the underlying
important family mapping for the North Coast.
And in the next version of the SSI l map, we will
look at deferred matters across the rest of the state.
Jumping into the variables that we
looked at to help build the SSL map.
The first one is the land and soil capability mapping.
So this is a data set that pulls together the best available
souls and Natural Resources mapping across New South Wales.
So it provides a broad scale regional view
to the dominant land and soil capability.
And it's built on eight key Soil and Landscape limitations.
So soil types like land composition, acidity,
salinity, drainage, roughness and climate.
The land is then given a class ranging from one to
eight, and one being the best land or land that has
the less amount of limitations right through the age
which is predominantly the nature conservation areas
and borders and pretty much national parks areas.
The next map flag that we were using to help build
the criteria is the inherent soil fertility data lab.
So this provides an estimate of the well of the
inherent fertility of the soils across New South Wales.
So it's based on a five class system from low
through to high and it was derived from linking
soil fertility to a particular soil type.
We then use P page and this was
done at two different depths.
So zero to five and five to 15 into that area.
We also acknowledged that water availability is
obviously here, water is king in the agricultural world.
And so we've used a limit of 500 Notice of rainfall or
above, or lands that are within a certain distance to
reliable surface water being either regulated rivers or
stream water greater than five, and productive granules.
So many of these layers will help, we'll use to help build
the basis that was created back in 2012, or 13, I believe.
And so we've just expanded on those criteria and data sets.
And we also know that there's not a one
size fits all across the whole state.
So what we've done is we've ran a series of different
scenarios, where we use a variety of models to mix the
criteria to identify the SFL S A L across the state.
So for example, where rainfall was higher, but soil
fertility was lower, that would be identified as where soil
fertility was higher, but rainfall was less reliable than
you did a strongest for fertility or soil type in that area.
So we also just want to point out that the basis of
these mapping is on the resources of the land and
climate, the inherent characteristics of that land.
It doesn't pick up land management, so we acknowledge
that some biophysical characteristics such as soil
pH can be managed to make the land more productive.
However, management practices rely on the activities
of that particular landowner, and should ownership
change, then the land management might change.
So that's why we're just looking
at the inherent capabilities.
Oh, that's there.
- Just go away again.
Everybody here, I might just walk through
the exhibition page that we have here.
And just show you where you can provide
feedback and what we're looking for.
Just jump in.
So here, we have the landing page for the exhibition page.
So a bit more background as to why we're
doing it and that it's development.
Here we have, sorry, scroll a bit bar, the SSI l map.
And we'll go into there in a minute.
Here's an opportunity also to complete a survey
to provide more details about the map in general,
rather than specific points on the map, and also
to register for further updates on the project.
Because as we mentioned, this is just the first
stage and it will be a rolling development.
So here are some documents that
we will be that are available.
So a short summary on the methodology that outlines
the criteria that I just mentioned, should you want to
just go in and have a look at the data sets that I use.
And also here is the report from the Agricultural
Commissioner that outlines the recommendations.
Down here, we also have a series of frequently
asked questions that you can we encourage
everyone to just jump in and have a look.
And hopefully it might answer some
other questions that you might have.
- So when we jump into the map itself, just greeted
with it with a welcoming statement just here.
You can see that you can read the map, move it around.
In zoom in and out, we would like to have a look.
But we want to emphasize that regardless of which level
A map is viewed at its precision is basically determined
on the quality of the data used to create the map.
So you might notice that some areas
are more accurate than others.
And this is predominantly because of
the underlying data that was used.
Some are more false than others.
But the map at the present is very broad scale.
And it's designed to use for strategic
planning purposes at the local regional level.
It's not suitable for property specific planning, such
as assessment development proposals or spot rezonings.
So that will require a greater level of accuracy.
So in those areas where the data is less accurate,
that's where we would love to hear feedback from you.
And that can be done in a variety of different ways.
So if there's something that you like or dislike,
simply grab an icon and put it down where then we would
like to make a comment, filling the comment about what
you like or dislike, and, and further details there.
And that's how you provide feedback on the map.
There's also, if you have any ideas or suggestions or just
a general comment as well, should you want to just get the
outline of how to do that, just click on the how to use map
and it'll give you a step by step guide on how to do that.
Over here, we also have a bit more information
about the project, if you wanting to get
that background again, while viewing the map.
You also have the feedback activity.
So where somebody has come in and made
a comment, you can start a discussion.
Or you can like or dislike that comment.
And you can also go straight to the survey here.
So you can go straight to here and fill out the survey.
So there's a variety of different ways that we can have a
look at the map and provide feedback directly on the map.
Just close that one off.
Go back to the presentation.
So in this exhibition period at the
moment, what sort of feedback are we after?
We're looking to see if we've used
the right criteria for the mapping?
And if we haven't, what criteria is missing?
We're also looking at, is there any other data sets
that are out there that we we have not used yet.
So ideally, we'd like to use statewide data sets.
However, if there's data sets that are at the local regional
scale, then we'll certainly review those and see if we
can incorporate them in the next version of the draft.
If there's land that's not mapped as Sal, but
you think it shouldn't be, please let us know.
But if you could please provide an
explanation as to why it should be included.
And conversely, if it's SSL, a
melt, and it shouldn't be, please.
Yeah, provide some commentary around.
So that's the sort of feedback that we're looking
for in the development and map, as Colin Tamara
mentioned, it's definitely at an early stage.
But there's something like this, it's important
that we let people know that we're developing
this project, and we want to get community input
and industry and government input right across.
So I think that pretty much wraps up the map and how
it was developed and the sort of feedback that we have.
So I'm I came back.
- Thanks.
How long?
Have you been boattail?
And Mara, we've had a couple of
questions being raised in the chat.
Now, I'll direct a couple of these to both of you.
Helen, Alex asked whether environmental zones
biodiversity and Aboriginal heritage will be protected.
Can you just I think you've
touched on it in your discussion.
Can you give us a quick rundown how environmental
zones were considered in the mapping?
- Yes, so we've, we use environmental zones to just
identify where some SS Al is in there because of
those council areas that we're looking to rezone.
But then, in the next draft, we exclude areas
such as cultural and heritage and other areas
that might come into environmental sensitive
areas, and those sort of laser already taken out.
So they're not within the FSA on that.
- Thank you, Tamara.
Robert Shelley's asked the agriculture Commission's
report, this is the sequence of events.
First of all, revision of a map and a policy to go with it.
You touched on possible policy, when you
detach, you need the government's response.
Could you just elaborate on on that question, please?
- Yeah, sure.
So the report by the New South Wales Ag Commissioner did
sort of talk about the exhibition of a map and a policy
at the same time, so that we knew how it would be applied.
It's proposed that any future policy will be exhibited.
So this exhibition of the map is the first in what will
be a series of iterations to try and refine the map.
And so it is proposed that once there has been some
cross-government agreement as to what that policy might
look like that it will then be exhibited in conjunction
with the next iteration of the map, hopefully At this
point in time, we thought we wanted to start the process
of the mapping iterations to try and make sure that the
map got to the best possible format as quickly as possible.
And so we thought it would be prudent to get
the first version out on exhibition while those
government negotiations took place in the background.
- Okay, Helen, flood prone land and mining leases.
How is the map dealt with those two issues?
Combining a couple of questions here, just because
there's likely to start getting quite a few.
- Yeah.
So flood prone areas have been still included in the SSA L.
Because we know that some of the those areas are
grateful daring lands and other key industries.
So if the criteria match that, and it's
on flood prone areas, then it's still
included in relation to mining lace areas.
It's we haven't taken into consideration that at
this stage, but the next draft will be including
the any areas that spot development consent, or
disturbance footprint consent for mining areas.
So that will happen in the in the next draft.
- Thank you.
And as Tamara pointed out that the intention of the
map is not to replace the BCL map in the mining sector.
- So, yes, and I will.
So to add on that that also includes
the critical industry clusters.
So this map will not replace those
- Elen, the ANC plans suggested that the New South
Wales land use survey mapping may be helpful.
Have we used that as a reference?
Or could we?
- Yes, that's been looked at and incorporated, to cross
reference some of the information that we've got.
So we'll look a little bit deeper
into the next draft of that.
But it's certainly been a layer that we've we've
used to cross reference, but we've currently not.
- And where could people find further details of
each of their criteria, such as slope, did extended
rockiness Strange characteristics and things like that
during the biophysical characteristics of the land?
Yeah.
- So on the exhibition page there, and under the
Documents section, there's a summary statement that
outlines the methodology that we've used so far.
And in that document, there's a list
of the data sets that we have used.
And we've primarily used publicly available data that
everyone has access to, to go in and have a look.
And it has links to that.
So there's a dam at the New South Wales data portal,
we'll have a link to the land and soil capability mapping.
So if people go in there, then they can download that
data layer and have a look at the levels of rockiness
or acidity or the limitation that was used to determine
that particular land, land and soil capability.
- Thank you.
We what we might do is we'll keep going through the
chat questions, but could we get in quite a few.
But if anyone would like to speak to their
question, if you could raise your hand the
reaction chat reactions down the bottom.
And we might be able to, to talk through that bearing
in mind that we might take a little bit longer to get
through all the questions if we're talking to them.
They'll go on with the next one.
Tomorrow.
- The North Coast area the North Coast mapping is currently
used to inform rezonings and around urban areas.
Will this approach be continued with the
use of the SSA all maps are to be finalized?
- So thanks for the question, Natalie.
The way that the map will be
applied is yet to be determined.
But DPI do provide guidance based on the
best available information that we have.
And on the north coast.
There's a lot of community support for
the mapping as it currently stands.
And so we think that it's reasonable to consider that even
if the mapping, you know, is correct at a regional scale
and might have some edge effects, generally it provides
us an indication of where the most productive lands are.
And so we do use that to inform the responses
that we made to particular proposals.
I don't think that this will change.
I expect that we will continue to use the best available
data sets to inform the responses, you know that we made.
And I'm hoping that answers the
question and the intent behind it.
Natalie.
- Thanks, Tamara, Andrea, Roundtree, you would like to
you'd like to come off mute and ask your question.
- Yes, I was just wondering if we already know that
15% of the land in the state is producing 85% of
the agricultural projects have those areas already?
I mean, no, no, this is sort of trying to identify them.
But we already know where a lot of those areas
are, have they already been marked off on the map?
- Andre, I can have a go at answering
that Helens an expert in it.
But I'll have a go.
We we have an idea.
So the 15% is made up of various types of
industries that have contributed so yourself, I
think, from memory, you're in intensive livestock.
So that 15% doesn't actually include the intensive
livestock because that data set that the intensive
livestock production systems are not necessarily
reliant in my understanding at least and you know, this
better than I do, on particular soil characteristics.
So the available data sets that we had at the time and
still currently have a soil biophysical characteristics.
So what we're proposing to do, as an addendum to this
process is identify what we're calling production areas.
So those areas where there are clusters or
known intensive livestock systems that we
can then map as an addendum to this map.
So the 15% that I spoke about picks up things
like horticulture, and viticulture, and,
and some of those cropping areas as well.
Now, we don't know where all of them are.
And some of them may be intermittent as
well, you know, there might have been less
area crop during the drought, for example.
And some that have just used consistently because
they've got access to more reliable water.
So we've mapped as best as we can, where we think that
those that 15% is, but we're not, we're not 100%, just
because of the accuracy of some of the underlying data
sets, hence why we're hoping you guys will tell us
where we're right and wrong as part of this process.
I just, it'll be good for intensive livestock, because
it isn't dependent, exactly on the soil type and the
rainfall, but you we need the protection around the beam
that goes in there to not have conflict of land use.
So yeah, I think it would be really good if they were
not as an addendum that included straightaway showing.
They're already there.
They're already productive.
And we do need protection from all those other land uses.
So yeah, there's another part of the process that
we're doing, which is to identify buffer areas.
And one of the recommendations in the
report was that we make that a required
consideration in the planning framework.
So that there's mandatory consideration not
to say that the buffers have to be mandatorily
applied, but at least they're a consideration.
And what we're doing as part of that processing currently
is just having a look at our interim buffer guidelines,
and just determining whether there is enough scientific
rigor behind them, and how we can ensure that they are
fit for purpose and pick up the industries that we need.
And then providing an education program to councils
as well as consultants and the community around.
You know why it's so critically important to have
buffers around intensive livestock proposals.
The issue with the map is we don't
know yet how it's going to be moved.
So us so we could map the intensive livestock.
So the ones that we know about and and again, look based on
what's happened in the past with, you know, people having
intensive livestock is identified on a map and then having
people come along and vigilantism against those proposals.
It's difficult sometimes to try and map things accurately.
- We're already on a map.
So don't locations are not secret already.
But we there, there are no reciprocal buffer distances.
That's why we need to be on this map.
Because there's those buffer distances that people
you know, the DPI and various other government
departments have been talking about, and for years and
years and years, and they just haven't happened yet.
So please don't exclude us from this
process, because we need to be part of it.
- Yes.
All right.
No, thank you.
Look, we would do well, we're going to do everything
we can to try and make sure that there's less
land use conflict, like the trajectory of land use
conflicts was one of the key findings in this report.
And coupled with that, like the mental and
economic implications of that on the farmers
and the community and the landowners adjacent.
So we're going to do everything we can to
try and help that ladies conflict issue.
- Thank you both for that question.
A couple of questions relating to land
use planning and councils local strategic
planning, strategies and regional plans.
Tomorrow do would you like to talk to how we are
working with councils and DPI II Due to align
with regional planning work being undertaken?
- Yeah.
So the intention is not that the map picks
up land identifies as urban growth area
bound, like within the existing urban growth
area boundaries or for urban expansion.
So, if there are inconsistencies in our map with those
areas that are earmarked for expansion, please let us know.
And we'll make sure that we can, we can rectify that.
The intention, however, is to identify land,
which is of significance to the state in terms of
agricultural production in the hope that future
iterations of LSPs and regional plans direct
growth where possible away from these areas.
Now, that's not always going to
be possible, and we get that.
But where the where there is a possible alternative
location, we would hope that this map would help
in providing that guidance to say, you know, this
is really about valuable land for this purpose,
perhaps you can do your expansion in another
direction, or look density as a as an alternative.
So yeah, we're hoping to get consistency with the regional
plans as much as possible, the LSPs is a little bit
more difficult, we don't have as much oversight of them.
And there's quite a lot of them.
So again, really happy to take your feedback, if you
do see, council identified both areas, you know, Matt,
are happy to consider what's been said in that space.
And we also hope to be able to refine the map as the
LSPs is reviewed, and the regional plans, you know,
look to what the LSP PS is saying, as well as what this
map is saying and to try and get that harmony between,
you know, predicted growth areas and proposed growth
areas across the state and meeting those regional local
lender and state needs for agricultural production.
Thanks, Tamara, Lorraine Wilson, you put your hand up,
would you like to come off Newton and ask your question?
Thank you might be so we unmute the line, we can't hear you.
- Okay, I come from the Central Coast.
pedo.
And Tamara, I was really surprised when I looked at
the map the other day and discovered that there were
a lot of areas on this plateau it on this Plateau
Region that obviously had agriculture going on now.
But we're not signified with the cell outline.
And I take on board, what you're saying about local
governments needing to expand and subdivide, there would be
little like likelihood that our local council would want to
extend subdivision areas out on to our plateau, because the
cost of providing services out here would be astronomical.
So it's not an area, the only thing that is happening
here that is impacting his rural residential where
people with enough money are able to buy up previously
agricultural land to put a horse or two on, on for,
you know, teenage daughters and things like that.
But we have a huge nursery cut flower,
beef production, chicken, meat, stone,
fruit, avocado and citrus industries here.
And fours, a relatively small sub region of the
state, our productivity is, is quite, is quite large.
So my question is, two in two parts, I guess.
When you were mapping it, did you not have a look at what
was actually there in front of you on the Google Maps and
not recognize, improve pasture for instance, areas or, and
I go back to what the other lady was saying, obviously,
a lot of chicken sheds, which you're not prepared.
And I get it, we have been at the mercy
of animal laborers and things like that.
But we also need to recognize where productivity is.
Yeah.
Can you answer that question anyway?
Why?
Why you obviously did not mark where
farming production was happening.
Yeah.
And the reason is, we don't have the resources to look
at every single property and mark where production
is occurring at that scale at this point in time.
So this map is a very, very much a first pass.
We've looked at the existing data sets that
we've that we've had and ended the land use,
and Helen's just been through all of those.
And we basically overlaid them.
And then those areas that popped out
as meeting the criteria were included.
And those that weren't, we're not.
And there was, there was no team of 500 to go
through and go, You know what, this is a really
stupid outcome, we really need to fix that, because
we just didn't have one the local knowledge, or
Secondly, the resources and time to be able to do it.
So hence why this will be the first in
what will be a series of exhibitions.
And we desperately need that feedback from
yourself, because there's going to be areas that
we have mapped, which are less than productive.
I have two farms.
One kangaroo wants to pack lunch.
And the other one is amazing.
You can't walk through there for
the grass at the moment, both Matt.
And like, we know, that's because the
underlying data sets are not great.
And it's just a case of taking that local knowledge
and saying, Hey, look, this area is really important.
There's an export terminal proposed.
In Newcastle port, we're looking at a sap
which relies on agribusiness production.
So we need protected productive areas within proximity
to enable economic transport of the goods and the like.
So that we can when we are starting to look
at a review of this map, say, hey, look,
there's a heat more pressures on the coast.
And we know that there are and potentially,
if we've got an extra bit of land that comes
out here, maybe we could put that in there.
Now we can't map the whole of the state.
The intention of this map is to say this part
of the landscape is critical to agriculture.
The other part of the landscape, perhaps can serve
alternate purpose like tourism and whatever else, but this
part we really want to protect so that we can intensify
and not have land use conflict and provide certainty.
So we're very mindful that we want to keep it a very
targeted map with a percentage, or with an area of
land map that we know, you know, is of superior value.
And also, you know, we can provide those planning,
I'd say protections or that planning direction
around this is the preferred future use for this
land, you know, and still enable other other uses
that are that are needed to occur elsewhere as well.
So, so no, sorry, I've gone off track a little bit.
But no, we did it nicely advised.
Spread this map around to all the New South Wales
farmers members up here, and our chamber of commerce
members and alert people in the local little
newsletter and say, for heaven's sake, right.
Go on with and make sure your places
murky, you know, Yep, absolutely.
Yeah, absolutely.
And we need that, because we just, I mean, I'm not
guaranteeing that comments will be taken on board, we
might not make changes, because we might not have the
data to be able to support making that particular change.
But if we don't have the information to say it's
wrong, or it needs fixing, or it needs this to begin
with, then we just can't even look at that, you know,
so very much please share it around to get as much
feedback to us as possible, we would love to hear it.
When we're not precious, we're not thinking
that this is perfect already by any stretch.
So please,
- I have to be honest to the desert number of those
landholders would be hoping to subdivide at some stage.
In your region, there's a big push for rural
residential, you've got one of the biggest
problems across the state we're facing at the
moment is rural arrays around your region.
So look, and that's it.
But again, it's critical.
You've got rural readers, and people live there with
an expectation of a rural residential lifestyle.
And if someone puts a poultry farm or there
is an existing poultry farm next door,
you know what they smell, there's trucks.
It's noisy.
And and that's what we're trying to prevent.
So is that is that land use conflict?
And yeah, so yeah, please, any feedback
that we can get in that respect?
I like to eat chicken too.
And it's cheap.
So you know, and it's cheap.
So people buy it.
That's right.
Thank you.
Thank you tomorrow.
- I might just build on that.
On.
Following on that is that another recommendation
from the agriculture commissioners report is to
potentially look at industry production areas.
So it might have been heard of IPAs?
So that's a second mapping project that DPR investigating.
So that would pick up sort of key industries that might not
fall under the biophysical map of the FSA al at the moment.
- Thanks, Helen.
Just a couple of quick questions, Helen.
I wrote a few together from the chat again.
There was a question about small areas of land
being mapped and and being included on the
map as well as a question about some of the
vineyards in the Hunter region not being mapped.
Could you talk to those questions, please?
Yeah, sure.
So the the map that's being developed at the
moment, we primarily just putting the criteria and
determining what land popped up based on that criteria.
When we do that The next few iterations that will
dissolve some of these small areas, so we have to
then go in outside whether they get incorporated
or taken out depending on the size of school areas.
So that's why it is a bit of a mottled effect in some
places in relation to that, say vineyards or, for
example, if you've got a blueberry farm or something,
it depends on whether the criteria fit into that.
So we haven't targeted this map
based on a particular industry.
So if an industry doesn't sort of fall within
that, those biophysical characteristics that were
falling across the stage, that it may have the
possibility to be picked up in the IPA process.
That was the best second recommendation
from the Agricultural Commissioners.
I do want to re emphasize, though, for the viticulture
industries, will around the hunter area, though it does
not cancel out the critical industry cluster there.
So thanks, Helen.
Another couple of questions.
Just before we go to you, Sam, the there's a couple of
questions in the chat about buffer distances and buffer
guidance, broadly speaking, and now the agriculture
commissioners report did make a recommendation about
DPI having a look at the you know, the issue of buffers.
And that is a piece of work that DPI will be
doing in parallel with this with this map.
And just quickly tomorrow, there was a question about how
the mapping aligns with the large scale solar guidelines.
Current SSD developments for solar and wind projects,
would you quickly talk to that for go to Sam?
- Ah, yep.
So look, the the currently the large scale solar guidelines
that have been adopted by a DPI a planning, talk about
avoiding land and soil capability classes 123 were possible.
That's that's the only public guidance at the moment.
Currently, there's no as mentioned earlier, there's
no policy in how this map will be applied or how
influence particularly development decisions,
or even the strategic planning framework.
So at this point in time, the answer probably is from a
regulatory point of view, there's no nexus at this point
between the map and where those proposals are going to go.
Now, I'm not confident that that's going to
be the position that's taken by the community.
And in particular, particularly communities,
community sentiment is seeking from what we're
hearing, at least, that product or cultural land
should necessarily possibly be excluded, where
possible from coverage by solar farms and the like.
But, I mean, the the issue that we have
is that the currently there is no policy
about how this that will be applied.
So we can't use the map to
influence existing SSD applications.
What I would say is that the map has
been based on a criteria that's known,
so existing map data sets that are known.
And those map data sets are in the public arena and have
been interpreted for production of this map, but also
gives a fair indication of land which is productive.
Now, crudely, we've referred to land and soil
capability classes 123, just for ease, and
we'll probably will continue to do do that.
So to some extent, but there will be a lot of
consistency between land, soil capability classes, 123.
And these map as well.
So while the map in and of itself doesn't have
a regulatory role, what I would suggest is that
he does indicate where, at least on paper, some
of the best agricultural lands in the state are.
And that might then lead to some sort of community
expectation that that land might be considered
for agricultural purposes as a higher priority
in relation to some of those applications.
But I guess the short answer is there
is no relationship at this point.
- Thanks, Tamara.
Sam Dempsey, would you like to come
off mute and post your question?
- Yeah, thank you.
So I'll just have the 15%.
That's a high yield for the
agricultural production industry.
When when we've looked at this
10 year period from 2007 to 2017.
Is there a filter that can be applied to look at the
land use change just to capture where remnant forest
has remained where it's potentially been cleared?
Or to be able to, I guess, benchmark how the industry
is positively contributing to land use change.
- Thanks, Sam.
So we are proposing a monitoring process
once we can get this map finalized.
But in terms of land use change in terms of like
the use of agricultural land particularly, and
you know, conversion to plantation timber or
some other type of carbon capture initiative.
It's not proposed at this stage
for this process to capture that.
The monitoring process that we're proposing is to be
able to understand how much of what we're identifying
as SSA l might be lost in any year to agricultural
production, whether that's through conversion to other
permissible uses in the rural areas like mining or
solar, or whether it's to urban encroachment and the
like, and then understanding why that has occurred.
You know, in, like we said, in
some cases that might be necessary.
But at this stage, we're not proposing a process.
As part of this map, at least, to be able to quantify that
land use management provisions, having said that, it will
be possible, looking at some of the data sets that O H and
API in the life use for the regulatory mapping, I think
that it would be possible and probably worthwhile doing.
But I have not got enough staff
or mind capacity at this stage.
To contemplate that for more than happy
if you want to provide that feedback.
We're always looking at how we can improve the processes
and the decision making information that we have.
- Thank you.
I just had a follow up question.
I understand that you're saying that down the
line, you'd look to potentially include a second
addendum to intensive livestock or looking at
the IPAS don't the timeline to that would be?
- I'd like to say yes.
But I really am.
I'm reluctant to commit like,
what it's going to depend upon.
So I have a team of seven staff.
And we have a series of projects that have come
out of the recommendations of the commissioner
as well as work that we do in terms of referrals,
and, you know, working with industry and the like.
So the IPAS project.
I love the IPAS project.
It's one of my favorites.
And I would love it to be occurring right now.
But I just can't resource that
while we're doing this project.
And then the other thing is, as well, I guess
there's going to be some key learnings from this
project and the mapping data sets that we have in
the like, that will then inform the IPAS project.
And also the negotiations across government too.
So if if a decision is made across government that this
map has no regulatory effect, then the IPAS might not
benefit from being identified in this process only it may
well be that we identify them and apply them on a regional
scale, or we talk to council about their identification
and then recognition in their LPs at a regional scale.
So there's a lot of uncertainties at the moment
just based on the uncertainty around this mapping
process and how and how it's going to be applied.
And I note that there is some frustration in
some of the other questions in the chat around
the policy and, and how the maps to be applied.
And, you know, we're we're in sort of the same boat to
some extent as well, ideally, we would have known, and we
would know by now what what the maps intended to inform
and how much weight it's going to have in the like,
but irrespective, we think there's a lot of value in
mapping, what we consider state significant agricultural
land, and we'll continue to run that process while
that policy position is developed across government.
Thank you.
Thanks, Sam, Tamara.
Kylie, if you could just put up the last slide again,
I know we're getting close to the end of our time.
Has anybody got a burning question they'd like to
ask or can take a couple more from the chat if you've
got something that you'd like to raise your hand?
- One of the questions haven't from the chat
related to identifying the criteria on the map.
You know, like whether the, at the moment
when you look at the map, it just uses.
It's just blue shading over the land.
And there's no indication of why that land
has been shaded, you know, as alignment with
the criteria that we you spoke to earlier.
Could you talk to that point, please?
I know, this was raised a couple of times.
- Sure.
The reason that we couldn't put up the data
sets that's for the whole state with the
underlying data that helped build it is too big.
To be honest.
It's close to over two gig.
And so you wouldn't be able to move
around or have a look on the map.
If there's a particular area that you would
like to get an understanding of what criteria
has put it in on or knocked it out of SSL.
Please provide a comment or send something through
to the email address and we'll be able to provide
some information after the exhibition period
about the criteria that was used to determine it.
- Thanks, Helen.
So just to recap, public exhibition will be running
into the 31st of January and also in the chat there was
discussion about engagement with with the agricultural
industry, we will be holding another webinar in early
January, conscious of the fact that lots of farmers are busy
with harvest at the moment and or struggling with floods.
You can provide feedback by completing the survey or making
a comment on the map, or providing written submissions
by 31st of January to the SSA or feedback at dpi.
Email address.
And then once the exhibition is finished, will
were we trawling through the submissions and
looking at any necessary amendments to the map?
Knowing that we are out of time there, we'll go
through all the questions in the chat after this.
And and if we do anything we haven't covered,
we'll put a response to it in our Frequently Asked
Questions section on our webpage and exhibition page.
And so I think if this there's any last burning questions,
if anyone wants to raise their hand and speak to or not
call that call, close that webinar, they're certainly used
to get your hand up, or is there anything else you want?
Or something new you want to talk to?
- Or not?
I just left it up.
But I just had a thought just following PowerPoint there.
Could you Is there a way just to apply like a filter to
just show like, one lens to the map, like you don't want
to I guess have six different colors coming off at once.
At least if you could say, well, this is most
applicable to me, this is what I'd like to say.
- I'm working investigate the different layers that
we can put in but knowing that there's so many
different criteria, it's hard to determine what
different people may or may want to save themselves.
So because it was built using a whole variety
of different data sets that yeah, just it's
just too large at this stage, so but yeah.
- Thank you.
Okay.
Thanks, Sam.
Thanks, Helen.
Thank you all for attending today.
Stay tuned on our exhibition page for updates
and feedback, there's a area there where
you can register for further information.
And we already have a list of over 500 people,
stakeholders here to email addresses that we can we
can send invitations out to or more information out to.
So yeah.
- We've had quite a few questions coming up
in the chat or try and address some of them.
Now.
A question about slope, Helen, and
the data set used to identify slope.
Could you talk somewhat where that
that information has come from?
- Yeah, so the data set that we used was, it's the same
data set that was used for the native vegetation mapping.
So identify as land that's above 18 degrees slope.
So we've only made a cut off at 18 degrees at present.
We also have a slope read that goes right across the state.
And we will be looking at potentially using
a lower threshold in future if 18 degrees
is deemed too high for this particular map.
- So if there's land appearing that people think is high
is steeper than 18 degrees, let us know in the in the
submissions or on the map, and then we can investigate that.
nother question about intensive industries tomorrow.
Would you like to tackle that one?
Whether they've been accounted for in this process?
- Yeah, no, and that's a great question.
So and it's something I probably should
have mentioned in the earlier slide.
So I know, the intensive industries haven't
been picked up in this mapping process.
This process has been based purely
on biophysical characteristics.
There's an intention to map what we're calling intensive
production areas identified production areas, where we can
look at where there are clusters of some type of development
or alternatively, particular industries that need to be
identified on a map and and have some type of level of
consideration in the planning framework addition to this.
So it was decided to split the two to enable further
work to be done for those industries is that enabled
us to get the physical map out in an earlier stage?
Just to make sure that we had some level of
consideration of the biophysical characteristics
while we go through a process of working out how we're
going to deal with those industries that are not so
reliant on like the intensive livestock and even some
of the The intensive cropping industries as well.
So the agriculture commissioners report that
was released, it had 13 recommendations.
And in those, there's recommendations around education,
the identified production areas I spoke about, but
also buffers and consideration as to whether there
should be a mandatory consideration of buffers in
the planning framework, when proposals are within
proximity to existing agricultural enterprises, as well.
And so as part of that process, we are currently having
a look at reviewing our interim buffer guidelines to try
and give them a bit more scientific rigor and strength.
And then try and raise their profile a little
in the planning framework as well to as
another way of stopping land use conflict.
Thanks, Mara, and the information that was
collected with the important agricultural
land process between 2017 and 2019.
Can you talk how that was it that's
been considered in this in this map?
- Yeah.
So the land the information that was collected as part
of that process, looked at a couple of different facets.
So it looked at some biophysical work, as well as collecting
specific industry information for industries in those
regions so that industry specific information in the regions
will be helpful for informing that identify production areas
project, and some of the biophysical information that we've
collected helped us determine what some of the methodologies
settings might be as part of this process as well.
- There's a question about the relationship between
assets, OFAC soils, we have been talking to other
sections of government, other agencies of government
that do a lot of work in the SSL faceoff space.
And we'll be working with them to make sure that our mapping
correlates with what they know as well as a sulfate soils.
Question tariqa, I just like to build on
that one in that some of the low lying
areas are used as quite good, daring lands.
And so whether there's potential for assets or bad soils,
if it's not disturbed, then we will keep that as SSA L.
I also just noticed that comments in relation
to the the slope again, it's 18 degrees and 32%.
So they're the same thing.
So I'm just clarifying that for those who
were working between degrees and have you
got on that always confuses me, I'm afraid.
The question is a couple of questions relating to
the relationship between SS map Sal and urban areas.
There's in relation to existing urban areas, some of
the SSA Oh, but that urban land and could potentially
be considered as a issue with land use conflict.
Tomorrow, would you like to talk to that?
And maybe how the SSA or map could assist in
resolving land use conflict in the future?
- Yeah.
So the intention with this map is to
identify the resource and where it is.
So it may well be that does about urban land in some
places, I actually think I saw some questions as well
about identified urban growth areas and whether it was
intended that the map overlay there and and now it's not.
So if you do see any areas where we have included
the mapping over identified urban growth areas,
please let us know, because that's something
that we can fix as part of the next iteration.
But in terms of separation from existing urban growth
areas, the issue will be if if we separate them that from
those growth areas and set it out a bit further, those
growth areas, because it's intended potentially to be used
in the strategic framework, those growth areas, learning
proach to the boundary, again, will then have to move
that back again, and then again, they would encroach.
So there's a risk of creep, unless we actually
identify the resource and where it is at the moment.
Now, it may well be that there is land use conflict,
which would arise if there was a higher level of
intensive production on the boundaries, and that would
be have to be dealt with at a site specific level.
But in terms of the actual resource, I think it's
important to identify where it is not covering areas
which have been identified for future urban release.
But just to help guide with that future
urban release might seat it tomorrow.
Question from one on the council relating
to the economic viability of land.
This is something that they won't really rule lands
committee has been very strong in advocating for.
Could you talk about how the viability of land might be
considered or isn't considered at this stage in the NSA?
Oh, man.
- Yeah.
So I assume that the viability of land is a reference
to the scale of the lots on how large some of them are.
Yeah.
So there's a whole heap of work been done in that
in that space at the moment across various councils
where I'm where my daughter is bringing my phone,
across various councils where, um, you know, there's
a whole heap of existing fragmentation particularly
in the coastal zones, and not mapping that land is Sal
would mean that that land would again continue to be
fragmented, whereas it might serve a useful purpose in
facilitating some type of small lat intensive production.
So whether it be like obviously intensive livestock might
not be suitable there, but it may well be suitable for
share farming, some sort of emerging niche industry,
there's a lot of emerging industries that don't require a
lot of land, particularly on in the outskirts of townships.
So cut flowers, for example, one, mushroom farming
and the like, can occur on quite small lots.
So I think there's a there is an issue with economic
viability, but often councils turn to diversification
into other non agricultural pursuits, like tourism and
the light within those landscapes and, and that then
in turn, can prevent those lots actually being used, or
adjacent to those lots of being used for intensive and
agricultural purposes because of land use conflict reason.
So if you've got an existing fragmented
landscape, please talk to us.
So we can work out what you know we can do to help you.
Or if there is anything that we can do to help you
to try and make sure that the best agricultural
land remains in sort of productive use, while also
ensuring that you know that you've got the room that
you need for growth and whatever else it is, the
council might envisage as their as their future.
Sorry, but the short answer is no, no
consideration of economic some or the exclusion
of smaller existing lots at this stage.
- Thank you tomorrow.
I also know Brian, I think I saw your hand pop up.
If people would like to speak to their questions.
Ellison Did you please.
Click on the reaction button down
the bottom and raise your hand.
And we'll try and get to you as well.
Alison, do you still want to talk to your question?
- Yes.
My question was regarding how does the SSI Oh land
interact with the state significant renewable energy
mapping that way now in which central wastes are not as
most buried under the state's significant agricultural
land, but we're now been inundated by renewables?
How will that interact so that we can coexist?
- Thank you.
It's a million dollar question.
Allison.
I'd be happy if you've got an answer to that.
Look, we met with some of the proponents of some solid
developments yesterday that are both mapped as Sal
as well as being within the renewable energy zones.
And at this stage, the purpose and application
of the map has not yet been finalized.
So there is no clear mandate as to
how his proposal should be considered.
And each at the moment is currently being
considered on its individual merits.
So I think there's a we had a similar
question in the webinar yesterday.
And, and there's a regulatory aspect to it,
which is that the map does not have at this
stage, a regulatory purpose in that space.
But then there's a community sentiment purpose as well.
And there's a fair bit of concern about
social licence in the renewable energy zones.
And the last thing that that we need in those
zones is loss of social licence because of a
perception of loss of, you know, the sustainability
of an industry due to fragmentation or the like.
So, look, it's a great question.
And happy to talk to you more offline about that, because
it's an area that, you know, we're working quite closely
with planning in at the moment, and you're keen to try
and get a resolution because there are competing interest
entities driving divide at the moment across communities.
- Thanks, tomorrow, we'll go back to
a couple of questions from the chat.
There's a couple of questions relating to whether
urban and industrial land has been excluded.
It has but the zoning has been taken as of June 2020,
I think in color from from memory, so any land that's
been rezoned or industrial as urban or identified as an
open release area, since then, may still be showing up
as being mapped as SSA L So, so if there are areas out
there in your council, LGA that, you know, have been
identified for urban purposes since then, let us know.
And we will look at that with the next version of the map.
Another question relating to how this map will feed
into the North Coast Regional Plan and also the
review of the Greater Sydney regional plan as well.
Tomorrow, we'd like to talk to that issue.
- Yeah.
So there's a slight conflict of timing at the
moment with the North Coast Regional Plan.
So as I understand it, it's out on exhibition now
or is it or about to go out on exhibition for review
and at this stage, our map obviously is in its first
iteration, and very much keen to hear your feedback
on how we can improve the map for the next iteration.
But until this map is in a form where we're
more happy that it's accurate, it won't
be used to replace any mapping product.
And then, So following on from that the North
Coast mapping, we'll continue to use the existing
North Coast important agricultural land mapping,
important farmland mapping until such time as
this product is agreed to be a replacement for it.
And its accuracy has been, you know,
confirmed or at least accepted.
So similarly, with the Sydney in the Sydney
area, we did consider the use of the Metropolitan
rural area as potentially entirely being mapped.
But we did note that it picked up areas that
were used for urban areas in the life as well.
So we determined not to do that just because
it would impact the ability to apply certain
planning controls across the breadth of SSA L.
The intention is, as I mentioned earlier, any existing
urban growth areas, or areas identified for future
growth purposes, should be excluded from our map.
So please, if they're wrong, please identify them.
But yeah, hopefully we'll be able to help better inform
some of the planning in Sydney though there's been
quite extensive planning down in that region and and
particularly regionally specific planning as well.
We know that there's issues with food deserts in Sydney,
and even land that's not mapped as SSA Oh, we'll be able
to help contribute to that region's food and fiber needs,
as well as demonstrating and educating the community,
the broader community down there around agriculture.
- Thanks, Tamara.
Hello, and a couple of questions
about the functionality of the map.
There was a point raised there that a comment
made a little while ago hasn't shown up on a map.
And also do people get notified when they when
they comments when I make a comment on the map?
- Yes, so we're getting quite a few
comments come through, which is fantastic.
That's the feedback that we're after.
So we they do get reviewed internally by
dpi before they get put up on the map.
So quite often a bit more of a genuine statement about
them that then a feedback will go back via email to
yourself and might not necessarily show up on the map.
But you will certainly get notified for that.
If it's a comment made on a particular area.
So saying this area should or should not be included.
That information goes up on the map for people to
elaborate on or start a discussion, or like or dislike.
So where it usually takes a few days to get
through some of the comments, but definitely
would get your you will get feedback.
- Thanks, Alan.
One other comment or question related
to the the timeframe for exhibition.
exhibition has been extended until
the 31st of January next year.
So there's still time to to make submissions.
Also, we been informed, but we
will with the harvest requirements.
And also with the flooding that
we've had in western New South Wales.
Just recently, many people who had registered have been able
to make these webinars so we will be holding another webinar
in early January with penciled in the 13th of January.
So the information on that one and registration details
will go up on our exhibition page in the next week or so.
So look out for that.
If there's somebody you know, who wanted
to attend, but hasn't been able to.
Was there anybody else who wanted to raise their hand and
speak to a question or any issues that are burning for them?
- Might just raise mine quickly.
Saudis.
- Oh, sorry.
Hey, Rhonda.
I, did to actually if you can hear me, Amanda.
Yes.
Go ahead.
It takes a little while for your for your name and
image to pop up to the top of the to the screen for FTC.
So yeah, go ahead.
- Okay, thanks.
I'm disconcerted to hear that.
If farmers alter the pH of their land to make
the lane more productive, that is totally
disregarded, because the lane might change hands.
I mean, surely farmers should be encouraged
in increasing the productivity of the land
and also encouraged to dryland farm in a very
productive way by planting deep rooted legumes.
no till farming.
There's a lot of things that farmers can do with
dryland farming that makes the land productive.
Yes, I can see that that land is not
recognized as being of significant value.
I can see on the map and it's very significant.
- Yeah, tomorrow, would you like to answer that question?
- Yeah.
So thanks, Amanda and look god, yeah, fully
supportive of the use of regenerative or other farming
methods, which do make the land more productive.
And look, it would be great if we could recognize that.
So the maps intended to be at this
stage applied at a regional scale.
Some of the underlying data sets are very
limited in terms of the input layers being
at like one to 100,000 map scales at best.
So to go down to a cadastral level and see how poor farming
practices have improved, the landscape in particular areas
would probably not work in terms of some of those other
underlying data sets that we're having to use as well.
It also means that we would end up with a
landscape where we might have a well managed
farm here and mapped and one here, not mapped.
But that's not to say that we don't encourage
productive farming practices, either.
The mapping of the land is SSA L is not meant to
mean that the other land is not as productive mapping
land, farmland by any stretch of the imagination,
there's, there's certainly areas that are going to
be used for dryland cropping, which might not be
mapped in those areas, which at this stage may be
mapped, which potentially aren't productive at all.
Also, if you do know of areas of the landscape
where things have been improved, put a note
down, and we can have a look at that as well.
Because I mean, it may well be that
the underlying soil set isn't that bad.
If it can readily be converted and and made more
productive, then it may well be that we have an
opportunity to move things around a little bit and
include that land at the expense of some other land
which may be mapped and isn't quite as productive.
So we'd really love to know from you where they are.
But we just can't guarantee that we can look at
a cadastral scale at each of the of the farms
and and say Your time has been managed well.
And you know, and even if it did change hands
just change hands would still be productive
probably for a decade or so, before it did revert
back to potentially what it might have been.
So yeah, came to came to hear where they are.
So we can see what we can do about that.
But just in terms of the scale of the mapping at this
point, we can't look at it at an individual site basis
to do that, you know, maybe in some future iteration or
that the maps intended to be reviewed on an ongoing basis.
We know that production methods change, there's climate
change going on, you know, there's obviously acidification
and changes in rainfall patterns, which I think have been
in some of the other questions that have been up there.
And so there's a, there's an understanding that the map
will need to be updated on a fairly regular basis to as
that information changes and better data becomes available.
So you know, at some point, there may well be a
resource where we can map to a cadastral ale or not.
And I hope that we do get to that point, because that
would be really helpful from a planning point of view.
But yeah, at this stage, we just
don't have the resource to do that.
- Well, that's that's a shortcoming of the
whole process, though, isn't really there yet.
I mean, you're making decisions really
about the land that may be incorrect.
- Yeah, so and so that's the point of
having the map applied to cadastral.
Sorry, at a regional scale to be to begin with before it
is recommended for any type of application at a DA scale.
And it might never get to that point.
So we recognize that there are
those shortcomings in the mapping.
But from a point from the planning point of view,
and from the point of view of the consultation that
that we did with the broader community, and with
councils as well, we thought it would be better
to have a product out there, that might be 80%.
Right?
To enable us to start a discussion as to whether there
was a need in the planning framework to recognize
agricultural land, we're seeing increasing amounts
of agricultural lands converted to other uses.
And it's a case of do we want to identify
where we think the better agricultural land is.
So we can, you know, ensure intergenerational productivity?
Or do we say, Look, we're never going to have the
data sets to be able to have it identified on a
cadastral basis, so we just won't do anything.
And I think that the better outcome is to have
a map which isn't perfect, but could be made
better over time, then to not have anything and
not be able to influence the framework at all.
- Thank you tomorrow.
Katie, you met Robert to film AFI is got the handout.
Katie, would you like to make?
So ask you a question?
- Thank you, Paul.
Question, it's probably slightly out of scope of this
particular consultation process, but just wondering what the
future consideration is for land that's adjacent to a cell
or B cell that might have beneficial services to that land.
So I think we should put a comment in the questions there
about land that could be providing ecosystem services
like being an important biodiversity reservoir or could
be important for water management of that Sal, is there.
I know it's not part of this particular map.
But is there an intention to try and include those
kind of adjacent services in future planning?
- So I'm happy to take that one.
And thanks for the question, Katie,
and also for the question in the chat.
Look, the intention.
So the purpose of this map is to identify states if
you're going agriculture, to land now, there's some
levels in some areas in the rural landscape which
serve multiple purposes, including environmental
functions and whatever else the case may be.
And but the you know, at some
point they might be recognized.
And I think, this process in an ideal in my ideal
world, and it might not be the view of government,
we haven't had those negotiations yet, but would
be to identify those areas, which, you know, have
a preferred future use for productive farm farming.
And there's other areas of the landscape then which
might be identified as having more of that rural
landscape value, and they may be your environmental
assets or an environmental management perspective.
So I'm hoping that, that this map is the first in a series
of maps or a series of processes where we can ensure that
the rural landscape is identified for its multitude of
functions in a similar way to the way that the residential
areas and the industrial areas are segregated into
this type of residential or this type of industrials.
You know, it's a clear area of work that needs to be done.
And you know, and it would be great to be able to say
these maps going to say this, you know, preferred future
use here is Enviro, here, it's going to be landscape here,
it's going to be prime and production, we just haven't
again, got the resources to do that in this first pass.
But certainly, I hope that this is the
start of a larger process to better
allocate the rural landscape to those uses.
Thank you.
And I just and I might just jump back.
Sorry, Amanda, one thing I didn't mention in response
to your earlier question, and just to allay concerns is
that one of the proposals that we're looking at is that
for a site on a site specific basis, people can request
a review of this map if they think the land has been
mapped, and it's impacting upon them, and they don't
want their land mapped, or, alternatively, they want
their land that we're proposing to introduce a process,
you know, once a map is finalized, where you can write
to us and say, Hey, I don't think the mappings right?
You know, I think you need to change it.
And those are the reasons why.
And we'll look at an individual basis at those requests,
and then update the map accordingly as necessary.
So I'm not sure if that sort of adds to that.
But I guess it's probably a bit of
important information to have as well.
Yes.
Sorry.
Sorry, how long?
- Yeah, it's just building on what Tamara was saying.
Yeah, a verification process will go Go ahead,
which then will be reviewed by a team based on
the input data that's supplied to help support it
either being included or not included in the map.
Okay, thanks.
Thanks.
Hello, Sally Whitelaw.
Would you like to ask a question?
- Yeah.
Thanks, Paul.
Look, it's just about the important fallen North
Coast when I was born across to the new map.
So it looks as though for around Coffs
Harbour there might have been some changes.
So just curious, it's been hard to tell, because the
scale, the curious if there have been changes underneath?
And what methodology that that changes might have been made?
Ellenwood, would you like to start on that one?
Yeah, so the North Coast family mapping was an
input data layer that was brought in as a whole.
Then there was also areas in the north coast that
were identified using the statewide criteria.
So that might not necessarily be
picked up in the farmland mapping.
So the new areas that you're saying is
based on the criteria for the whole site.
Okay, tomorrow, there's a question in relation to the
future timeframes for further iterations of the map,
and whether councils will be able to, or whether anybody
will be able to provide further comments at a later date.
Can you talk to that issue face?
- Yeah, definitely.
So we're hoping to have the next iteration of the map out.
We were hoping initially for April, April, May.
So we'll still say that we're aiming
for April or May for the next iteration.
And we're hopeful that by then we will have a policy
position that we can exhibit at the same time.
So we can get feedback on both the map within the
context of how it is proposed, to potentially be applied.
And, and there was some concern, I also saw in, in
the commentary about its application or cadastral
basis, initially, look, I just don't see that being
its first application, I think we want to have a
fair level of comfort at regional basis before we
apply it, you know, mandatorily or cadastral basis.
So look, I'm not going to guarantee that's not
going to happen, but I'm quite confident in that
the map will be applied, potentially in a strategic
framework first, just to make sure councils
are happy with that, and landowners as well.
But definitely there's a proposal that will
exhibit the policy and the map in sort of
April May next year is its next iteration.
- Thank you, Tamara.
Helen point was made in the comments about federal Gramer
photo grim Gramma tree and multispectral imagery and
the use of that type of technology to inform the map.
I'm hoping that you can talk to those
issues rather than good, I can't.
Can you give us a rundown on whether those type
of things can be used or how that fits into the
public, publicly available data that we've used?
- Yeah, thanks for those data sets are very useful for looking
at picking up different land management and other criteria.
Definitely, it's, it's a bit of a challenge
to use them over a full statewide application.
So currently, we just use the statewide information
that's publicly available at this stage, because we know
that there'll be a verification process down the track.
We've also just started this process with a preliminary map.
And depending on the resources that we have available,
we'll look at other data lines that we can fit in.
But certainly, if we can use some infrared
and other other satellite imagery, that that
would be fantastic to help with accuracy.
But it will depend on what resources we have available.
- Thanks.
And I think that that issue of having the most up to date
information, or building a map based on the information
we have to hand, it is also demonstrated in another
comment in the in the chat there that at the moment,
the best we've got is a five meter pixel rate faster
for the for the slope lands, but there is a new, sorry,
we've got a 30 meter pixel raster for the slope layers,
but there's a new five meter one coming out next year.
So so that's the type of information we were
looking for in in the, in our submissions, as well
from other agencies is, is where you have more
or better information that can inform this map.
We'd love to be able to use that so that
we can make it as accurate as possible.
Yeah.
When when is finalized.
Tomorrow there was a question about cropping versus grazing.
In the in the chat there, the a lot of
land looks like to be favoring the cropping
land, whereas grazing can be occur on land.
It's not necessarily mapped on the map as SSI.
Oh, would you like to talk to that issue, please?
- Yeah, absolutely.
So there's the reason that we've picked Well, the reason
that the map is current, currently covering cropping, or
land that he's perceived to be able to promote cropping
as opposed to grazing country is that as you've pointed
out, in the question, grazing can occur for animals on a
on a wide variety of soils and a wide variety of slopes.
So cropping, however, is limited to only those areas,
which, you know, are suitable for cropping, you know,
fairly flat, fairly clean access to water and the like.
So the intention is to identify land, which is of state
significant salt provides an economic return to the
state, some of our key export industries and the like.
And then can be used for a variety of purposes as well.
So I've got some country here that I'm looking out over
at the moment that has been cropped in the past, at
the moment, we're using it for fattening at some point,
we might turn it back into cropping land, but it's
good enough, but it could be used for both purposes.
So we're grazing country is important.
And certainly, you know, we've got a breeding
enterprise as well, that uses slopey land,
that wouldn't be any good for fattening.
Also we couldn't crop it.
So while it's important to recognize that, you know,
grazing, sorry, having breeding country is important
to any cattle operation, it's also important that we
identify the land that can be used for a multitude
of uses, because if we identified all of the country,
you know, across the state or a larger proportion
of it, we couldn't have targeted planning controls.
And the intention behind the map is that we enable
it to be used in the planning framework to have a
stricter array of planning controls, potentially, or at
least a higher level of consideration for agriculture.
And then there would be other areas of the rural landscape,
which are still considered agricultural lands, but maybe
I will to do additional things, you know, which may be
slightly incompatible, then the higher intensity uses
that might occur on the land that's mapped as Sal, I
know, that's a long Wofully answer to your question, but
effectively, it's about having, you know, quite a targeted
subset, which is supported by those other lands as well.
And as I've sort of said earlier, we're not walking
away from the remainder of the rural landscape it's
critical, you know, as a nursery and whatever else it
might be, whether it's for cattle, sheep, or the like.
We know fine grain wall is grown, you know, on some
sleepy country and poor country, but we just can't
identify all of the land so we had to identify
that land which could serve both both purposes.
- Thank you, Tamara.
question relating to notification of landowners, a
lot of rural landowners don't have internet access.
And so viewing the map will be difficult.
We hadn't intended to write to all landowners
in the state, which state government or
DPI doesn't have the that information.
But we're quite happy for councils to.
Not to write to people, but to help spread the word.
If they have newsletters, and we
can talk to individual landowners.
If they Yeah, they can't access the map that we have there.
We're just we've got about four minutes left of our time.
Is there any other question that someone would like to
speak to that they have that we haven't covered yet?
We've had a lot of questions there in the chat.
And I've frantically been trying to cover them all.
But I'm admit, I probably missed a couple.
Is there anything anybody would like to ask Kirsty?
Just have to come off mute Kirsty, we can see I can
see your hand right, that says sorry, clicked it
but it didn't take but I'm just wondering what the
timeframe is for including intensives and what the
process is and how we get involved in the conversation.
- So yeah, so Kirsty, we're very much in
early stages of that process at this stage.
And I would really would really welcome
any input that we can have to that, when we
get to a point where we can take feedback.
Look, I envisage that that process won't commence,
you know, with any real vigor until probably 2023
at a guess, just because we're nearly in 2022.
Now, and it's going to take us I suspect
most of next year to finalize this map.
I have quite a small team.
And we are working quite hard to try and get this
map as well as some of the other components, the
education components and other components that
are sort of recommended for us to undertake done
so look very keen to have input from anyone that
wants to give it to us in relation to that process.
So if you wanted to send us your your details
cosi, we're happy to put you on a list.
You know, we're going to have steering groups and
project committees on the like for that project.
So really keen.
If you want to be involved in that.
That'd be great.
Thank you.
- Thank you, Kirsty.
Thank you, Tamara.
Carly, could we just put up the feedback slide, please,
- Mark, just that quickly there, Paul, just to further
build on some of the things Tamara has mentioned it.
This map is designed to look at the best of the best
land, so it's not picking up particular industries.
So just want to emphasize that the critical industry
clusters that are identified as part of the cell, which
is within the mining sector, this will not replace that.
So that's the viticulture CIC nv f1 CIC.
- Thanks, Colin.
So just just a reminder for the feedback public
exhibition is open to the 31st of January.
As we mentioned, there'll be another
webinar in early January, keep an eye on
the on the social pinpoint site for that.
You can provide feedback by completing the
survey or putting a comment on the map.
The functionality of the map, being able to drop comments
onto your particular parcel of land is really good.
So while you're in there, zooming
around, having a look at it.
Give us give us your feedback on your land as well.
And of course, we'll take written submissions
until the 31st of January, as well as
the SSA or feedback at DPI email address.
Once we have all that those submissions and the
exhibition periods, close, we'll work through them
all, we'll look at all the data that we have any
new data that we can use to make the map better.
And we will look at you know, tomorrow said
looking at doing another version of the of the
map for exhibition in April May of next year.
So it was it is no other burning questions.
Anybody has a notice?
- Oh, can I just add one more thing?
And he's just asking that in the question about to
what extent councils will have a say in the maps versus
owners in broadacre areas and both parties will have
equivalent say so if you could please provide any feedback.
Both councils and landowners have the same
pathways to make comments to us on the map.
And certainly we value the input of landowners
because you know your country and you know, you know
what it takes to run it so please don't hold back.
Let us know what you think.
And that way we can try and get the best product
that's gonna serve industry which is you know,
what we're about as much as being able to make
sure there's a good planning outcome as well.
- Yeah, and then if they We'll be going through all the
questions in the chat over the next couple of days.
And as I said earlier, anything that we
haven't addressed, we'll make sure it goes
into the FAQ is on our exhibition website.
So with that, I thank you all for your attendance today.
And we'll wrap up the webinar there.
Thank you very much, everyone.